Hello again.
Every half a year, we talking about
what's new in Shopify connector and
every time we have something to add and
usually it is in the following areas.
API updated.
Happens this time again. We did
something better for our product
information management, for order
management and for customer management.
Basically the same story today.
I will start and continue with a number
of different demos.
Let's have a look on
item list.
I have item list. Let me open this
specially prepared Athen desk.
And I just choose add to Shopify.
Okay.
That was easy. Item was sent to Shopify.
Do you want to look at it? Yes, but we
will look at it from the Shopify admin
center instead.
And I will go to the list of products
and I will find my new Athen desk as it.
I will open it
first and scroll down.
There are plenty of fields, prices,
inventories, SKU all populated.
But hey, something new is here. It's a
shipping. It's a information about a
country of origin and harmonized system
code, which is in Business Central
actually equals to tariff.
Let's go back to item card in the
Business Central, scroll down to the
cost and posting because foreign trade
is hiding here. So, we have a tariff
number with a country US. So, this
information is now sent to Shopify as
well.
Let's go to the Shopify shop card
and explore item and product
synchronization part. So, we have a new
toggle which instruct system to import
and export tariff codes. When we
importing tariff codes from Shopify,
they will not be created automatically.
System will try to map it. They need to
be present in the your tariff list. If
not, then it will be ignored. So, auto
creation is not happening here.
But,
otherwise, synchronization is a fully
working.
What else do we want to see in this
in this section?
There's a new field usually
hidden and
I need to need to add it using
personalization, which is called find
mapping by barcode. Apparently, in some
installations in the Shopify product
using the same barcode.
And if
SKU mapping did not work,
then connector when import this items
continue to search by by barcode and
search in the item references.
Sometimes it leads to the effect that
multiple different variants or items are
connected to the same
uh
item variant entity in Business Central,
which is
not desirable, so you can disable this
one. Then mapping will not happen. You
need to map it manually. But, better
than incorrect mapping. All right. What
else?
The status. Shopify introduced new
status, unlisted.
In this case, product is in Shopify. It
can be sold, but nobody can see it. So,
it's not in the online web
store.
But, if people got the direct link, they
can perform the transaction. So, we
support
status as well. Yeah, so once items are
pushed to Shopify, the status is
in this case, unlisted.
All right.
What else we want to try here?
Let's Let's do following. Let's choose
synchronization and choose a sync
prices. I will do it here, but I know
that everyone can figure it job queue.
And it runs.
Notice when I run it here in foreground,
I immediately got notification that
something was skipped.
Just wanted
show it to you.
Apparently, variant for this specific
item is not synchronized because item is
blocked.
Show me the record.
Mhm.
It's blocked where? In sales. Yeah,
sales blocked. When we calculate prices,
we create temporary sales quote
using other parameters and of course we
cannot create sales quote if item is
blocked. So, you cannot calculate prices
as a result.
So, this item will be
missing. Job queue if you run job queue,
still will be marked as a successful
because it just ignores this item. So,
if you notice that some items are not
synchronizing,
I suggest to go and check skipped the
skipped records.
How to do that? Yeah, you can navigate
search for skipped records from
anywhere.
Or, we also added a queue on the roller
center.
Let's scroll down. Now, Shopify
activities is very very very long. Yeah,
but it also now includes skipped records
and API errors. So, if you have any
errors during synchronization, you will
see some numbers here. So, makes sense
to take a look from
at this one from time to time. And it's
easier than jumping to to stores and
explore them one by one.
All right, how did we learn about that?
Because somebody told us about the the
problem. How people can actually talk to
us.
Two ways.
And it's a a bit confusing.
Let me go to Shopify shops.
If I will open the store
and choose actions
and access and leave a review, this is
review which will appear on Shopify app
store. We don't have much information
about
who wrote it and
what is the problem. So, when people
complained there, we have very limited
ability to contact them and and help.
But, there is another button,
provide feedback.
That's our Microsoft specific button
where we can actually give a complaint
or report a problem about Shopify, and
it allows you to
provide detailed information, which will
not be publicly available on Shopify App
Store. It will be only visible to
Microsoft Development Center team.
And
you can add extra details, for example,
screenshots or attached files, and you
can also decide if you want to be
contacted back.
So, that's uh
another trick on if you want to share
some feedback and want it to be
acted on, that's a
good way to do that. But, back to the
Shopify connector demonstration. Now,
let's switch to a different theme. So,
now we go to the B2B.
Shopify made B2B available to all plans
with some restrictions. Like, not every
capability is available, but from our
perspective, all but one capabilities is
available. So, that's why B2B company
synchronization is now visible by
default.
And uh
you can use it. For example, you can
just go
to list of companies
and add a company.
This one.
And it will be sent to Shopify.
So, this company is created on Shopify
together with a
customer
and catalog. This one, auto create B2B
catalog toggle is only available for
plus and advanced plans. So, it's
something which is not available for
different
for simpler and cheaper plans, but maybe
it's not a
big problem because there is an
alternative. What am I talking about?
We are in Shopify admin and we are
looking at the list of markets. Now,
this is a relatively new concept
for Shopify couple of releases ago
where you can define market and market
is actually not only geography,
sometimes it also POS locations
or it can be also specific customers,
B2B customers. They also can be grouped
into the market. And the recent
addition, it's the channels.
Let's take a look. And for market, you
can actually use catalogs as well.
But catalogs are special because they
were appeared in the Shopify before
market, so they have two flavors.
So, you can see catalogs like the last
four catalogs, they have different
icons, but they are all market catalogs.
Yeah, so they market based on the
region,
market based on B2B, and market for POS.
But there are two catalogs
with a some building icon which are old
B2B catalogs. And you can see that my
Adatcom Corporation was automatically
created because I activated the toggle.
And that's pretty
good way for
for merchant
to ensure that once customer and company
created on Shopify, they can use prices
defined in the business center accurate
ones. Especially if you define like
individual prices, like each company has
individual prices, then this
method
catalogs linked to B2B location is
is a good and reliable one. Let's take a
look again.
I can create catalog
and then I have two options. I can
create catalog for market and then
markets are different ones or I can
decide company location. Again, company
location is only available for plus
customers.
Yeah, it's a little bit of a intro, but
I wanted to show you.
I mentioned that it's very good idea to
create B2B
catalog if it is linked to very specific
customer. But what if not?
Look, I have another catalog which it
was originally created for Adventure
Works East,
but then somebody decided to add it to
Fabricam
North as well. Yeah, I have a
couple of companies with multiple
locations.
All right. So, now I connected it to two
different company locations and save it.
Let's go to Business Central. I will go
to related B2B catalogs. Right now, I
see only one which I just created and
exported and you can see it as it has
information about customer. So, it means
all price calculation logic will be like
not defined here, but coming from
customer directly. So,
price group, discount group, uh
if uh prices are including taxes or not,
so like everything coming from customer
information.
And associated catalogs
in Business Central. All right. Let me
get catalogs.
And I did not get any more. Like why?
Because we definitely saw that there are
two on on Shopify side.
Let's take a look at the tool tip.
And it's very small, but I will read it
for you that it actually says that B2B
catalogs are only imported if
corresponding company present in
Business Central.
Okay.
Definitely, I don't have my
uh Adatum customer. We remember that
once we've been here,
uh we only had Adatum, but not Adventure
Works or not the second one. Let's
choose synchronize companies.
Okay. Now, we got Fabricam and Adventure
Works. That's a good news.
All right. Now, let's try again and go
to my B2B catalogs and get catalogs.
Now, we will get one extra catalog, one
extra catalog, but listed twice. That's
a problem. Problem because what if
somebody decides
to use different discount groups?
All right? And we saw it actually uh at
customer interviews, and then decides to
synchronize prices.
All right?
In this version, we are starting
preventing this situation because it
make no sense because it's only one
catalog on a Shopify site, and even if
it's a listed twice in the Business
Central because it's associated with two
different customers, catalog is the one.
So, we cannot
populate it with a different prices,
and the last one will be overwriting all
previous things. So, makes no sense. So,
here we are giving a better guidance,
recommending people to switch to market
catalogs instead,
because in this case, they are
dramatically easier to manage. Just a
less problems in the future,
and less less confusion in the UI.
Let's jump to the
companies list.
Let's see what what I imported.
Maybe we just go to
company and locations.
And I can have a my main company with
location, and I have tax registration
ID. Yeah, so we import this information
for a long time already, and we use this
information when we import it, when we
are
mapping
Shopify company with Business Central
company. But what we are we're not
doing, or not doing great, if company is
missing in customer is missing in
Business Central, when we created it, we
did not populate the field.
And there is a very good reason because
our connector is uh
same for all countries. There is like
one country
where
VAT
uh
registration number was not supported,
and it's Belgium. Why? They have a local
field.
So, our functionality didn't work, and
it when it tried to write information
into the VAT uh field,
it got the error.
So, in this release,
we still have Shopify connector
W1 version, same for everyone, but we
are releasing two small extensions, nano
extensions, I would say. One for
Belgium, and one is for US.
You cannot find them in the AppSource
because we are using different way to
distribute it. So, that's why you will
see something like this one,
like this notification, install Shopify
connector extension,
and the same for Belgium. If you are in
Belgium or in the US. So, we have
different extensions, which are adding
couple of capabilities. In Belgium, what
happens, it will extend
and will extend the company tax ID
mapping. It will add a new option,
enterprise number.
So far, we looked at product and
inventory management, feedback and
review, and B2B functionality,
especially for plus customers.
What else?
We have two more demos. Let's take a
look at the order demo. I'm in the
Shopify shop store, and I will scroll
down to order synchronization, and there
is a new field,
use Shopify order number.
Sounds interesting. Yeah, we we have a
Shopify order number in the sales
documents already as a separate field.
You can also populate it as a
extra line,
but uh
it was a very interesting idea uh
proposed to
uh our partners. they like kind of to
use Shopify order number. And we can do
that. Yeah, of course, in this case, we
need to ensure that the invoice and the
sales order documents actually support
manual number
numbers.
I'm not using invoice in this
demonstration, so we'll just activate
it.
Now, I will navigate to my orders.
And this is my order, already imported.
And I will choose a create sales
document, but before I will do that, I
will choose personalize.
And try to add couple of more fields.
Which ones?
Contact numbers. So, now contact numbers
are actually
available.
They are populated automatically.
And you can change the values
if there are more than one contact
available.
All right.
Sell-to, bill-to, and ship-to contacts,
you can populate them here.
But, all right. Next, let's create a
document.
And sales order is created.
And it's still using the old number
because uh,
this order was imported before I
activated the toggle, the setting use
Shopify order number was inherited from
the from the setup and it's still off.
It looks non-editable, but I need to
unlink my
and mark this document as non-processed.
And now I can activate it and try again.
Create sales document.
Now, we can see Shopify number series
here. So, in the list of sales orders,
this one will look differently.
So, probably makes sense to review your
Shopify numbers and make sure that they
are compatible with what you use in
Business Central. Otherwise, sorting
might be interesting.
All right.
Let's open this document once again.
Let's take a look at the lines and what
we can see here is one line.
One line.
That's all what I wanted you to to
remember. And then we scroll further and
we can see here two lines.
It's definitely different. Why? Let's
take a look in the Shopify.
And I can see my order and if I open it,
I can see that actually the originally
sold item
which was called first
was returned.
And in exchange, customer got another
item which is called exchange.
Which is cheaper, by the way. So, the
the remaining amount was added to
customer to store credit store credits.
And now I'm importing this order.
All right. So, I already registered the
fact that the first item was sold and
it's present in my sales order. Now,
let's go to refunds. But before we go
there, let's go back to
stores, scroll down into refund and
return processing and see the action
process return as credit memo.
What else can poss- can be done
differently? We can also choose return
order.
All right. Now, let's go to refund.
Open our refund which, by the way, has
two lines. You can see that item which
was returned has quantity positive one
is returned
and exchange item is also present here.
Let me create sales document.
And
document is created of type return. I
can also do the same with the credit
memo, but now if you are using advanced
warehouse
you can also process returns here as
well.
All right, because credit memos are not
compatible with uh
directed put away and pick and other
warehouse scenarios.
So, now you got a return order which
looks the same. It has two lines. One is
a positive, one is a negative. Business
Central is powerful system. It actually
okay with this setup. You can actually
post it
and document will be registered. The
credit memo
registering fact of something to be sold
instead. But maybe
you want to do something else.
And there is a button, again the
standard one, move negative lines. You
can choose this one and decide how do
you want to handle the negative lines. I
want to send them to order or to
invoice. Yeah, because this is a return
order, then by default value is order.
For credit memos, the value is invoice.
But order is good.
And I always forget to reopen my
document before doing that.
Reopen document and
back to prepare, move negative lines.
Okay.
Sales order is created.
Which contains my exchange line.
And my And the price is 160.
And the return order was modified. Now
it has only one line.
So this is how we are handling exchange
returns and order edits as well. So the
additional sales can be created from the
refund as well.
Product and inventory management
covered. Feedback and review covered.
B2B and advanced catalogs covered.
Order import.
Document creations.
Tax details. I knew I was missing
something. Let's go back to Shopify
refund and what you can see. You can see
the tax fact box. This is a pre-release
version in the reality this fact box
will be down. So we can see some
additional information.
Plus we can see tax lines right in the
Shopify refund as well.
Okay, I don't have any tax in this sales
transaction.
What else? What else? If we go to the to
the related order, you can also find
something new. If you scroll down to the
invoice details, you can see tax
included. Yeah, that's a old one.
Channel liable, also old one.
But tax area code and tax liable are the
new ones. So, now they are present in
the document itself. And you can
override these values. And in this case,
the standard mapping will not be
triggered. Yeah, so I can decide that
I'm going to use this tax area code
and it's a tax liable.
All right. So, So, when I will be
creating document, this information will
be used in created sales document next
time.
Do I want to populate it manually?
Probably not. And for this one, we have
a separate session or separate video.
You will find link in the in the
description.
All right.
That's That's it. And thank you for
watching.